- [Instructor] Great,
so we have our player
movement set up pretty well.
And you can see when we
move the player around,
we can move it all around this platform.
So now what we're gonna do,
is we're going to introduce
more difficulty into this little
game by adding in enemies.
If we right click on the
hierarchy, create a 3D object.
And we'll make another sphere.
So you can see here our
sphere has actually gone
underneath the platform, so we'll bring
that up just a little bit,
and to make things easier,
we'll bring it up in front of the player.
And then we're going to just make
this as large as the player.
Just so we can differentiate,
we're going to just take one
of our other textures and
apply it onto the enemy sphere.
That looks pretty good.
We'll rename this to be an Enemy.
And then, we're just
going to bring this closer
to the ground, so let's
make this just at zero.
And then, we'll bring
this down to maybe .15.
And then, we'll just
make this an even six.
Now, we're going to add a
rigid body to this enemy,
so then that way both the player
and the enemy can
interact through physics.
So if we go to Add Component, type rigid.
We have a rigid body.
Cool.
So now, when we press
play, you should be able
to see the player runs into the enemy ball
and creates this little,
bumps it off a little bit.
So, what we're actually gonna do
is we're going to augment
the physics in small ways.
So, we're actually going to
go into our Assets folder.
Right click on Assets.
We're going to create a new folder
and we're gonna call
this Physics Materials.
Now, in our Physics Materials
folder is where we're actually
going to keep all the
different physics materials
that we might be creating
for our different objects in our scene.
If we right click on Physics Materials.
We're going to create a physics material
at the bottom and we're gonna
name this material Bouncy.
So if we left click and
drag bouncy onto our player,
and we left click and drag
bouncy onto our enemy,
we'll see if any effect happens.
So, you notice several things.
One, the friction is actually
making a huge difference now.
So, on our physics material,
we can actually apply even
more physics properties.
On our player, rigid
bodies can store things
like mass and drag and gravity.
But on physics materials,
we can actually change
the friction of how much
friction there is when something
is standing still versus
dynamic friction which is,
when it's moving, how
much friction is applied.
Or we can change the bounciness.
So how bouncy something will be
when it runs into something else.
So, since this is zero, there's not gonna
be a very large bounce effect,
so we'll set this to one.
And then, one of the other
things that we're gonna do
is under this Bounce Combine option,
there are different options
that you can select.
So, we can select the
minimum amount of bounce
that would happen when two things collide.
We can create the maximum amount
of bounce that would happen
when those two things collide,
taking the larger value
of that one or that one.
We can average it so
then it would actually
cut those values in half.
Or we can multiply it so
it'll increase the value.
So the bounciness of this
material and the bounciness
of this material will
actually be amplified.
So we'll make it multiply for now.
And then, we'll press
play and we'll see ...
... still have a bit of friction,
but the bounce is definitely a lot more
significant now which is really good.
Now, in order to check just
to make sure that you have
your bouncy physics materials
on each of your objects.
If you've got a player
under the Colliders,
there's actually a spot for the material
and that's where the
materials are applied.
So, if we do the same thing for the enemy,
you check their Sphere
Collider, and you can see under
material there's a bouncy
physics material applied.
So, now it's your turn.
You're going to create your own enemy.
Make sure you apply a new texture to it.
Scale it up.
Position it in your scene.
Make sure you rename it as
Enemy in your hierarchy.
Then you're going to go
into your Assets folder,
create a new Physics Material folder.
In that folder, you're going to create
a physics material called Bouncy.
On Bouncy, you're going to
change the bounciness value
to one and change Bouncy
Combine to Multiply.
And then you're going
to click and drag Bouncy
onto your player and your
enemy so they both have
that physics material applied.
And then you can test and see how bouncy
it is when your player
runs into another object.
Now it's your turn.